# **Graeme Haddow**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **Details**

Stirling, United Kingdom 07595841691 graeme@haddow64.com

haddow64.com

#### Skills

C#

.NET

ASP.NET

Azure

Web API

Razor

Blazor

**Entity Framework** 

SQL

Jenkins

Java

Spring

Gradle

JavaScript

jQuery

TypeScript

React

**HTML** 

CSS

C++

Microservices

Docker

Linux

Cypress

Git

GitLab CI

## **Profile**

Skilled and motivated senior software engineer with more than 5 years professional experience with the full software development life cycle.

A wide experience in multiple full stack environments including C# .NET and Java/Spring, using these technologies to deliver multiple enterprise level high volume systems. Committed to delivering great quality software and constantly learning new tools and technologies.

# **Employment History**

## **Senior Software Engineer at BT**

OCTOBER 2017 — PRESENT

- Lead the design and development of a set of common microservice components and user portals based on Docker and written in Java with Spring Boot to unify and simplify asset management within the organisation. This brought together what was previously a series of disparate systems and processes and built them on a common technology increasing efficiency and money saving measures.
- Development of a series of Web APIs in Spring to handle back-end processing of all IT and system access orders across the company.
- Wrote and delivered a system using C# .NET5 running under Docker for Linux to process Microsoft Teams telephony and location data to keep the emergency services database updated.

### **Software Engineer at BT**

JANUARY 2016 — OCTOBER 2017

- Delivered a C# ASP.NET MVC system to track and recover SQL server licenses that were no longer needed.
- Implemented a site written in C# with various Web API endpoints to onboard EE employees to the BT Active Directory domain after their acquisition by BT.
- Maintained a legacy classic ASP system to deal with the refresh and disposal of computing assets. Implemented TDD with NUnit to minimise the risk of regression issues to the legacy system.

### **IT Support Manager at BT**

AUGUST 2011 — JANUARY 2016

- Support of various editions of Windows Server (including Active Directory and Exchange server support).
- Developed a series of C# WinForms applications to standardize note taking, automate work logging and asset tracking. Delivering savings and increased revenue of over £72,000 P/A.

## **Education**

#### Computer Games Technology, University of Abertay Dundee

2006 — 2011

The undergraduate course focused not only upon game programming skills, but the skills required to become a well-rounded programmer with modules in agile development, network programming and mathematics as well as core modules in C++ programming.